kantarmedia.com 2019-12-29

# Privacy policy | Kantar Media

## Date created: Dec 2015 | Version 2  
Date revised: 1 May 2018

## Privacy policy

This privacy policy applies solely to the website pages located at www.kantarmedia.com/uk and www.kantarmedia.com/global. It does not apply to any other products or services provided by us or any other party.

This website is operated by Kantar Media UK Ltd. ("we" or "us"). By using and visiting our website and by submitting your personal information to us you agree to us using your personal information as set out in this privacy policy.

If you just want to know about how we use cookies please click here.

We respect the privacy of users of our website and recognise that when you choose to provide us with information about yourself, you trust us to act in a responsible manner with that information. This privacy policy contains important information about how we use your personal information.

### TV & Video measurement online

To view the privacy statement for our TV & Video measurement online solutions, click here

### Insights

To view the privacy statement for our Insights solutions, click here.

## What information do we collect?

At times we may request that you voluntarily supply us with personal information. Generally, this information is requested when you want us to provide you with information.

We may gather the following information about you:

  * Name
  * Email address
  * Telephone number
  * IP address (a unique identifier for your computer or other device)
  * Information provided by you in relation to submitting a job application to us (this may include sensitive personal information e.g. ethnic origin)
  * We may also collect data, including cookies, relating to your usage of this site, for statistical purposes and to improve the user experience on this site

## How do we use it?

We will use this information in the following ways:

  * to provide you with information that you have requested e.g. a newsletter, bulletins;
  * to provide additional information about our business or services which we feel may be of interest to you
  * to respond to specific queries you may raise regarding Kantar Media and its operating companies;
  * to provide you with better ways of accessing information from this website;
  * to process and consider your job application;

For how we use your information that is collected using cookies and similar technologies please see the "Cookies" here.

## Do we pass your information to third parties?

We may send your personal information to other group companies within Kantar, WPP, affiliates and third parties to help us process your personal information for the purposes set out in this policy.

We may disclose your personal information if we or any of our assets are the subject of a sale or similar corporate transaction. We will ensure that the third parties who receive your personal information are required to keep it confidential.

We may disclose personal information to third parties when we reasonably believe we are required by law, and in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual unlawful or otherwise prohibited activities, including, but not limited to, fraud.

## How do we use your information for marketing?

We will only provide information to you that you have asked for via the website.  This includes sending you occasional updates about our products & services, news and events from Kantar Media. 

## Where do we send your information?

You can be assured that we will protect your privacy.  This includes your name and e-mail address.

We may share your personal data with third party service providers, who help us track web usages on the website, process job applications, or send out electronic marketing communications. Where these transfers are across borders or outside the EEA we shall put safeguards in place to ensure the transfer is made by a legitimate method for the purposes of EU data protection law and secure.

Your personal information may be collected, stored, transferred or processed by our sister companies within the WPP group, or 3rd party service providers for data processing both within and outside the EEA. They are all contractually bound to keep any information they collect and disclose to us or, we collect and disclose to them, confidential and must protect it with security standards and practices that are equivalent to our own.

## How long do we keep your information?

Personal information will be retained only for such period as is appropriate for its intended and lawful use, in general we shall retain data for no longer than 24 months, unless otherwise required to do so by law. Personal information that is no longer required will be disposed of in ways that ensure their confidential nature is not compromised.

## Cookies

### What are cookies?

We may use information obtained from cookies or similar technology. Cookies are text files containing small amounts of information which we download onto your computer or device when you visit our website. Therefore, when we refer to "you" in this section we mean your computer. We can recognise these cookies on subsequent visits and they allow us to remember you.

Cookies come in many forms. We have set out below the main types and categories of cookies that are used. This section refers to all types and categories of cookies and not just those we use on our website.

If you just want to know which cookies we use please click here.

  * First and third-party cookies - whether a cookie is first-party or third-party refers to the domain placing the cookie. First-party cookies are those set by a website that is being visited by the user, the website displayed in the URL window e.g. www.kantarmedia.com. Third-Party cookies are cookies that are set by a domain other than that of the website being visited by the user. If a user visits a website and another entity sets a cookie through that website this would be a third-party cookie.
  * Persistent cookies – these cookies remain on a user's device for the period of time specified in the cookie. They are activated each time that the user visits the website that created that particular cookie.
  * Session cookie – these cookies allow website operators to link the actions of a user during a browser session. A browser session starts when a user opens the browser window and finishes when they close the browser window. Session cookies are created temporarily. Once you close the browser, all session cookies are deleted.

### What do we use cookies for?

Cookies fall into one or more of the categories set out below. This website uses cookies that fall into all the categories. Also we use data from targeting cookies placed on your computer by third parties when you have visited other websites.

  * Strictly necessary cookies – These cookies enable services you have specifically asked for. These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around the website and use its features, such as accessing secure areas of the website. Without these cookies certain services you have asked for cannot be provided. e,g, the ASP.NET cookie.
  * Performance cookies – These cookies collect information on the pages visited. These cookies collect information about how users use a website, for instance which pages users go to most often, and if they get error messages from web pages. These cookies don't collect information that identifies a visitor. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous. They are only used to improve how the website works.
  * Functionality cookies – These cookies remember choices you make to improve your experience. These cookies allow the website to remember choices you make and provide enhanced, more personal features. For instance, e.g. the ShareThis cookie provides ‘share this page’ functionality, where a user can email a link from a page to their friends. They may also be used to help provide services you have asked for such as watching a video or commenting on a blog. The information these cookies collect may be anonymised and they cannot track your browsing activity to other websites.

Targeting cookies or advertising cookies – these cookies collect information about your browsing habits in order to make advertising relevant to you and your interests. These cookies are used to deliver adverts more relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement as well as help measure the effectiveness of the advertising campaign. They are usually placed by advertising networks with the website operator's permission. They remember that you have visited a website and this information is shared with other organisation such as advertisers. Quite often targeting or advertising cookies will be linked to site functionality provided by the other organisation.

If you want to delete any cookies that may already be on your computer or device, please refer to the instructions for your file management software to locate the file or directory that stores cookies. If you want to stop cookies being stored on your computer in future, please refer to your browser manufacturer’s instructions by clicking “Help” in your browser menu. Further information on cookies is available at www.allaboutcookies.org. By deleting our cookies or disabling future cookies you may not be able to access certain areas or features of our website.

## Third Party Websites

Our website links to third party sites which we do not operate or endorse. These websites may use cookies and collect your personal information in accordance with their own privacy policies. This privacy policy does not apply to third party websites and we are not responsible for third party websites.

## How do we protect your information?

We take appropriate measures to ensure that your personal information disclosed to us is kept secure, accurate and up to date and kept only for so long as is necessary for the purposes for which it is used.

## Accuracy

We take all reasonable steps to keep personal information in our possession or control, which is used on an on-going basis, accurate, complete, current and relevant, based on the most recent information made available to us by you and/or by our client.

We rely on you to help us keep your personal information accurate, complete and current by answering our questions honestly and you are responsible for ensuring that the data controller is notified of any changes to your personal data.

We may contact you directly to confirm that the details we hold on you are correct.

## Rights of Individuals

To request access to personal information that we hold about you, you should submit your request in writing to the e-mail address or postal address shown below in ‘How to contact us’.

Under current EU data protection laws, you have the right to access, rectify or erase your personal information from our systems, unless we have legitimate interest reasons for continuing to process it.

From 25 May 2018, you may also have the following rights if we hold personal information about you:

  * Right to restrict processing of your personal information;
  * Right to withdraw consent to use your personal information.

If you notify us that you wish to exercise either of these rights we shall respond within 4 weeks. We shall also notify third parties to whom we have transferred your personal information of these changes. You may be able to access your personal information and correct, amend or delete it where it is inaccurate.

## Under 13-year olds

This web site is not intended or designed to attract children under the age of 13. We do not knowingly collect personal information from or about any person under the age of 13. If you are under 13 years old and wish to ask a question or use this site in any way which requires you to submit your personal information, please get your parent or guardian to do so on your behalf.

## How to obtain a copy of your information

You are entitled to ask for a copy of the information we hold about you (for which we may charge a small fee) and to have any inaccuracies in your information corrected. Please contact us using the details set out below.

## Changes to this privacy policy

We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions from this privacy policy at any time. You are encouraged to review this privacy policy from time to time.

## How to Contact Us

If your personal information or your preferences change or if you have any queries about how we use your personal information, please contact: [jon.ferro@kantarmedia.com](mailto:jon.ferro@kantarmedia.com)

## To protect your interests, we have appointed a Data Protection Officer (DPO)

Gillie Abbotts-Jones  
General Counsel and Data Protection Officer   
Kantar  
6 More London Place   
Tooley Street   
London SE1 2QY

## Complaints & Country Specific Disclosures: 

If you want to make a complaint about the way we have processed your personal information, you contact the Information Commissioners Office in their capacity as the statutory body which oversees data protection law within the UK – www.ico.org.uk/concerns.
